Islamic Arts Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Islamic Arts Slide Collection
1960-2005
VRC 1500
Yale University Arts Library
5
29 boxes in 5 containers
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of the arts of Islam, including architecture, ceramics, illuminated manuscripts, numismatics, and textiles. Includes materials from India and Spain.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of the arts of Islam, including architecture, ceramics, illuminated manuscripts, numismatics, and textiles. Includes materials from India and Spain.
Arrangement
Arranged by medium, then by country or stylistic designation.
Islamic arts; Slides; Reproductions
- Architecture (Box 1)
  - General [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
  - Afghanistan (Box 1)
  - Egypt (Box 1)
    - Cairo (Box 1)
      - Various (Box 1)
      - Plans (Box 1)
      - Nilometer (Box 1)
      - Tombs and Cemeteries (Box 1)
      - Walls and Gates (Box 1)
      - Mosques (Box 1)
      - Al-Aqmar (Box 1)
      - Al-Azhar (Box 1)
      - Al-Hakim (Box 1)
      - Barquq [Slide boxes 1-2] (Box 1)
      - Baybars [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
      - Hassan (Box 1)
      - Ibn Tulun (Box 1)
      - Kigmas al-Ishaki Mosque (Box 1)
      - Maridani Mosque (Box 1)
      - Mohammed el-Nasir Mosque (Box 1)
      - Muhammed Ali (Box 1)
      - Qala'un [Slide boxes 2-3] (Box 1)
      - Qayt Bay [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
  - India (Box 1)
    - Various sites (Box 1)
    - Agra (Box 1)
      - Taj Mahal (Box 1)
    - Amritsar [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
    - Bhadresvar (Box 1)
    - Delhi (Box 1)
    - Fatehpur Sikri (Box 1)
    - Jaipur [Slide boxes 4-5] (Box 1)
    - Udaipur [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
  - Iran (Persia) (Box 1)
    - Various sites (Box 1)
    - Isfahan (Box 1)
      - Masjid-I-Shah (Box 1)
      - Masjid I-Jami (Box 1)
    - Qom [Slide box 6] (Box 1)
    - Shiraz (Box 1)
      - Sultaniya (Box 1)
    - Tabriz (Box 1)
    - Tehran (Box 1)
    - Yazd (Box 1)
  - Iraq (Box 1)
    - Baghdad (Box 1)
    - Samarra (Box 1)
  - Jordan (Box 1)
    - Khirbat al-Mafjar [Slide boxes 6-7] (Box 1–2)
    - Mshatta (Palace) [Slide box 7] (Box 2)
    - Qusayr Amra Palace Complex (Box 2)
  - Kazakhstan (Box 2)
  - Libya (Box 2)
  - Morocco (Box 2)
    - Fez (Box 2)
    - Marrakesh (Box 2)
    - Rabat (Box 2)
  - Palestine (Box 2)
    - Acre (Box 2)
    - Jerusalem [Slide boxes 7-8] (Box 2)
      - Dome of the Rock [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
        - Plans, Models (Box 2)
        - Exterior (Box 2)
          - Exterior Details (Box 2)
        - Interior (Box 2)
          - Interior View Down (Box 2)
          - Interior View Up (Box 2)
          - Mosaic Details (Box 2)
        - Haram al-Sharif (Temple Mount) (Box 2)
        - Mosque of al-Aqsa [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
  - Saudi Arabia (Box 2)
    - Mecca (Box 2)
    - Medina (Box 2)
  - Spain (Box 2)
    - Cordoba (Box 2)
      - Great Mosque (Box 2)
        - Plans (Box 2)
        - Exterior (Box 2)
        - Interior (Box 2)
          - Capilla Villaviciosa [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
          - Mihreb (Box 2)
          - Patio de los Naranjos (Box 2)
    - Granada (Box 2)
      - Alhambra (Box 2)
        - Exterior (Box 2)
        - Interiors (Box 2)
          - Baths (Box 2)
          - Court of Lions (Box 2)
          - Court of Myrtles (Box 2)
          - Cuarto Dorado Court (Box 2)
          - Hall of Ambassadors (Box 2)
          - Hall of Abencarrajes (Box 2)
          - Hall of Kings (Justice) (Box 2)
          - Hall of Two Sisters (Box 2)
        - Mexuar [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
        - Mirador de la Daraxa (Box 2)
        - Oratory: Mihreb (Box 2)
      - Generalife (Box 2)
    - Malaga (Box 2)
    - Medina al-Zahra (Box 2)
    - Seville (Box 2)
      - Various (Box 2)
      - Alcazar [Slide boxes 11-12] (Box 2)
      - Giralda Tower [Slide box 12] (Box 2)
    - Toledo (Box 2)
    - Zaragoza (Box 2)
  - Syria (Box 2)
    - Aleppo (Box 2)
    - Damascus (Box 2)
      - Great Mosque (Box 2)
    - Qasr al-Hayr al-Gharbi (Box 2)
    - Qasr al-Hayr al-Sharqi [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
  - Tunisia (Box 3)
    - Kairouan (Box 3)
    - Mahdiya (Box 3)
    - Monastir (Box 3)
    - Sousse (Box 3)
  - Turkey (Box 3)
    - Balat (Box 3)
    - Bursa [Slide boxes 13-14] (Box 3)
      - Mausoleum of Prince Musa [Slide box 14] (Box 3)
      - Ulu Camil (Box 3)
    - Edirne (Box 3)
    - Ephesus (Box 3)
    - Istanbul [Slide boxes 14-15] (Box 3)
      - Baghdad Kiosk [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
      - Cinli Kiosk (Box 3)
      - Fountains (Box 3)
      - Mosques, Various (Box 3)
        - Acap Kapi Mosque (Box 3)
        - Beyazid Mosque (Box 3)
        - Blue Mosque [Slide boxes 15-16] (Box 3)
        - Fatih Mosque [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
        - Laleli Cami (Box 3)
        - Mihrimah Mosque (Box 3)
        - Mohammed Sokollu Mosque (Box 3)
        - Selimiye Mosque (Box 3)
        - Shehzade Mosque (Box 3)
        - Suleymaniye (Box 3)
        - Yani Valide Mosque (Box 3)
      - Topkapi Saray (Palace) [Slide boxes 16-17] (Box 3)
    - Iznik [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
    - Kayseri (Box 3)
    - Konya (Box 3)
    - Rumeli Hisari (Box 3)
  - Uzbekistan (Box 3)
    - Bukhara (Box 3)
      - Madrasah of Ulugh (Box 3)
      - Tomb of the Samanids (Box 3)
    - Khiva (Box 3)
    - Samarkand [Slide boxes 17-18] (Box 3)
      - Gur-I Amir [Slide box 18] (Box 3)
      - Shah-I-Zinda Complex (Box 3)
    - Urgench (Box 3)
  - Yemen (Box 3)
- Armor (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Calligraphy (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous [Slide boxes 18-19] (Box 3–4)
- Cartography (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
- Ceramics (Box 4)
  - 8th Century (Box 4)
  - 9th Century (Box 4)
  - 10th Century (Box 4)
  - 11th Century (Box 4)
  - 12th Century (Box 4)
  - 13th Century (Box 4)
  - 14th Century (Box 4)
  - 15th Century (Box 4)
  - 16th Century [Slide boxes 19-20] (Box 4)
- Enamels (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
- Furniture (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Gems/Jewelry (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Glass (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Ivory (Box 4)
  - 10th Century [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
  - 11th Century (Box 4)
  - 12th Century (Box 4)
  - 13th Century (Box 4)
  - 14th Century (Box 4)
- Manuscripts (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous all periods (Box 4)
    General
    All file by title. All copies of a single title file together regardless of date
    - Assemblies of al-Hariri [Slide boxes 21-22] (Box 4)
    - Automata of al-Jazari [Slide box 22] (Box 4)
    - Book of Animals of al-Jahiz (Box 4)
    - al-Sufi, Book of Fixed Stars (Box 4)
    - Choicest Maxims of al-Mubashshir (Box 4)
    - Dioscorides, De Materia Medica (Box 4)
    - Kalila and Dimna (Box 4)
    - Nizami's Khamesh [Slide boxes 22-23] (Box 4)
    - Shah-nama of Firdawsi [Slide box 23] (Box 4)
      - Berlin Shah-nama (Box 4)
      - New York Shah-nama (Box 4)
    - Story of Bayad and Rivad (Box 4)
    - Sulwan al-Muta of Ibn Zafar (Zafar-rama) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous by dynasty (Box 4)
    - Abassid (Box 4)
    - Ilkharrid (1206-1353) (Box 4)
    - Jalayfrid (1336-1432) (Box 4)
    - Mamluk (Box 4)
    - Safavid (1502-1736) [Slide boxes 23-24] (Box 4)
      - Shah-nama of Tahmasp I [Slide box 24] (Box 4)
      - Haft Awrang (Box 4)
    - Seljuk (1037-1194) (Box 4)
    - Shibanid (1500-1598) (Box 4)
    - Timurid (1369-1500) (Box 4)
      - Miraj Nameh (Box 4)
    - Ottoman (1517-1806) (Box 4)
  - India: Mughal (1526-1858) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous [Slide boxes 24-25] (Box 4–5)
    - Hamzanama [Slide box 25] (Box 5)
    - Nizami, Khusrau and Shirin (Box 5)
    - Padshahnama of Shah Jehan (Box 5)
    - Known artists: (Box 5)
      - Balchand, act.c.1596-1640 (Box 5)
      - Basawan, act.c.1560-1600 (Box 5)
      - Govardhan, act.c.1604-1640 (Box 5)
  - Turkey: Ottoman (1300-1926) [Slide box 26] (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - History of Suleyman (Dublin ms.413) (Box 5)
    - Suleymanname (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 5)
    - Suleymanname (Topkapi ms. H.1517) (Box 5)
    - Known artists (Box 5)
      - Osman, act.c.1574-1595 (Box 5)
      - Sinan Beg, act. c.1450-1500 (Box 5)
- Metalwork (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - 8th Century (Box 5)
  - 9th Century (Box 5)
  - 10th Century (Box 5)
  - 11th Century (Box 5)
  - 12th Century (Box 5)
  - 13th Century [Slide box 27] (Box 5)
  - 14th Century (Box 5)
  - 15th Century (Box 5)
- Numismatics (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Rugs (Box 5)
  Xx Textiles [Slide box 28]
- Sculpture (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Textiles (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Woodcarving (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Writing (Box 5)
  Xx Calligraphy [Slide box 29]